Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio, 267139
  - Subseries A: Performances, 267144
    - "On withered fields, wandering still" Montreal, 2010; ID: 350.0081; 267377 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0081)
      L'Oubli de l'air installation by Lani Maestro
    - "On withered fields, wandering still" Montreal, 2010; ID: 350.0082; 267586 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0082)
      "L'Oubli de l'air" installation by Lani Maestro at Fonderie Darling. "The 2 CDs, as separate tracks, played simultaneously with continuous playback, allowing for new relations of sonic material to occur over time"
      Original format: (2 sound discs) digital, 4 3/4 in.
    - "On the first day of Spring..." Malcolm Goldstein, Discovery, March 20, 1981; ID: 350.0083; 267232 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0083)
      a) Interviews with Joe Bloom b) On the first day of Spring there were forty pianos (8 min.) c) Soundings for solo violin d) Interview e) On the first day... (17 min.) f) Interview g) Soundings (8.5 min.) premier performance
    - "...out of changes; Keeping Still; Mountain" rehearsal, April 10, 1997; ID: 350.0084; 267267 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0084)
      Rehearsal, L'Art pour L'Art- Winsen for Hamburg Concert cassette copy from DAT original (22'50") (begins after a minute of silence)
    - "Portrait de Malcolm Goldstein" France Musique A l'improviste, Anne Montaron, September 26, 2008; ID: 350.0085; 267358 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0085)
      Radio France. Chargee de realisation Beatrice Trichet, Assistante Dorothee Goll.
    - Pro Musica Nova, Bremen, May 8, 1986; ID: 350.0086; 267268 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0086)
      Side 1: Soundings (11'00"), Marin's Song, Illuminated (31'00") Side 2: The Edges of Sound Within (20'16"), Out of the Corners of my Eyes (8'43")
    - "qerneraq..." as in "Topography of a Sound Mind", May 1991; ID: 350.0087; 267269 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0087)
      "qerneraq; our breath as bones" and padloq text (English and Greek) from "Topography of a Sound Mind" WDR Koln
    - "Quatuor d'occasion" Improvisations at Wilder and Davis, Montreal, May 5, 2012; ID: 350.0088; 267388 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0088)
      Malcolm Goldstein, Josh Zubot, Jean Rene, Emilie Girard-Charest. Recording by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Demo CD" Montreal, undated; ID: 350.0089; 267372 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0089)
      Malcolm Goldstein: Violin; Rainer Wiens: Prepared Guitar.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein" Cagibi, Montreal., April 14, 2009; ID: 350.0090; 267375 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0090)
      Violin and Prepared Guitar Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein" Cagibi, Montreal., January 20, 2009; ID: 350.0091; 267390 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0091)
      Mardi Spaghetti. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Casa del Popolo" Montreal, October 26, 2005; ID: 350.0092; 267392 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0092)
      Violin and Prepared Guitar. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Casa del Popolo" Montreal., January 4, 2006; ID: 350.0093; 267389 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0093)
      Improvising Montreal Series. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Improvising Montreal Series, Casa del Popole" Montreal., January 3, 2007; ID: 350.0094; 267391 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0094)
    - Real Art Ways concert, December 5, 1987; ID: 350.0095; 267270 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0095)
      "Soundings"; "from The Life Cycles of Stones"; "Out of the Corners of My Eyes"; "The Edges of Sound Within"; "Vision Tree Fragment"
    - "Regarding the Tower of Babel" Hessischer Rundfunk Ensemble fur Neue Musik, September 17, 1997; ID: 350.0096; 267359 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0096)
      Premier Theaterhaus Frankfurt.
    - "Renga"- Composite, complete music., undated; ID: 350.0097; 267607 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0097)
      Composite of recordings 1, 2, 3, and 4
    - "Renga" Fall mix- Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source, January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0098; 267272 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0098)
      3 Improvisations- Mix for broadcast Malcolm Goldstein, Jean Rene, Rainer Wiens, Rene Lussier, Normand Guilbeault
    - "Renga" Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source (1 of 2), January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0099; 267273 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0099)
      Malcolm Goldstein, Jean Rene, Rainer Wiens, Rene Lussier, Normand Guilbeault Studio 12: Realization: Helene Prevost Techn: P. Plante and J.P. Bolduc
    - "Renga" Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source [2 of 2], January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0100; 267274 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0100)
    - "Resonances de Babel" French/English version of "Regarding the Tower of Babel", November 26, 2004; ID: 350.0101; 267360 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0101)
      Premier The Babel Ensemble, La Sala Rossa, Montreal. Jean Derome: Flute; Malcolm Goldstein: Violin; Frank Lozano: Saxophone; Jean Rene: Viola; Rainer Wiens: Guitar.
    - Roulette #1, March 11, 1984; ID: 350.0102; 267275 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0102)
      Side A: 1) Soundings 2) Vision Tree Fragment Side B: 2) Vision Tree Fragment (continued) 3) Jade Mountain Soundings
    - Roulette #2, March 11, 1984; ID: 350.0103; 267276 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0103)
      Side A: 1) El nino rojo 2) Soundings (coda)
    - Roulette (at Location One) NYC, October 15, 2003; ID: 350.0104; 267361 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0104)
      "Variation 2" Johannes Wallmann; "Opium fur T" Matthias Kaul (9'30"); "Two Silences" Malcolm Goldstein (23'40")(world premier with intro and comments); "-Z" Hespos ensemble, improvisation. L'Art pour l'art.
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" New Performance Group (of Cornish) Seattle, May 11, 1985; August 29, 1985; ID: 350.0105; 267277 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0105)
      Winter and Spring: New Performance Group- Thomasa Eckert- soprano, Roger Nelson- piano, Stuart Dempster- trombone, Walter Gray- cello, Matthew Kocmieroski- percussion at University of Washington Art History Colloquiem Summer and Autumn: New Performance Group- Paul Taub- Flute, Stuart Dempster- Trombone, Thomasa Eckert- soprano, Roger Nelson- piano, Walter Gray- cello, Matthew Kockmieroski- percussion at Seattle Art Museum Gemini G.E.L. exhibit
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" Real Art Ways, February 26, 1983; ID: 350.0106; 267293 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0106)
      Side One: 1. Summer (16'05") 2. Autumn (12'09") Side Two: 1. Winter (24'42") 2. Spring (7'30") Hartford Connecticut, Real Art Ways
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" Tape Collage Part, undated; ID: 350.0107; 267294 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0107)
      Side A: Summer (15'00"), Autumn (12'35") Side B: Winter (25'00"), Spring (7'30")
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" Tape Collage Part, undated; ID: 350.0108; 267362 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0108)
      Summer (16'10"); Autumn (12'10"); Winter (25'00"); Spring (7'30"). For Performance Use.
    - "Selected Violin/Voice Music", November 7, 1999; May 17, 2002; ID: 350.0109; 267295 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0109)
      Side A: 1) "my feet is tired but my soul is rested" (11'20") 2) "Soundings"(10'36") Musique Action, Vandoeuve les Nancy Side B: 1) "it were another) (1998) (13'27") Hessischer Rundfunk Frankfurt November 7, 1999
    - Signal to Noise Studio, Burlington Vermont, November 18, 2000; ID: 350.0110; 267374 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0110)
      1) "Soundings" overture (9'44"); from "Configurations in Darkness" (10'35"); 2)"gentle rain preceding mushrooms" (10'24"); 3)"Hardscrabble Sons" (13'10"); 4)"Soundings"(5'15").
    - "Sirens for Edgard Varese" Basler Schlagzeug-Ensemble, Basel, May 10, 2006; ID: 350.0111; 267382 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0111)
      Konzert zur Ausstellung "Edgard Varese- Komponist, Klangforscher, Visionar". Edgard Varese, Amadeo Roldan, Henry Cowell, Andre Jolivet, James Tenney, Malcolm Goldstein.
    - "Solo Concert: Focus Series 'Traquen Art'", February 9, 1990; ID: 350.0112; 267296 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0112)
      Malcolm Goldstein Solo: Optica Gallery Focus Series Traquen Art Malcolm Goldstein and Martin Tetreault, Montreal a) Soundings; b) Sounding the Fragility of Line
    - Souffles Concert, Montreal, April 7, 2007; ID: 350.0113; 267364 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0113)
      1) "Renga/haiku song series"; 2)"from Fragments of the Wall"; 3) "Where are we going when we're standing still looking backwards?!"; 4)"Soundings". Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - Souffles Concert, Montreal: Vida Simon and Jack Stanley's loft., January 31, 2003; ID: 350.0114; 267363 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0114)
      "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (12'14"); "Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?!" (11'44"); "Hardscrabble Songs" (9'55"); "Soundings" (6'13"); "coda (like a prayer)" (3'11"). Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Sounding the New Violin" #1 Dia Foundation, May 5, 1989; ID: 350.0115; 267297 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0115)
      "Eight Whiskus" John Cage; "Sounding the Fragility of Line" Goldstein; "Trinity" Ornette Coleman; "Violin and Video" Joseph Celli "Sounding the New Violin" #1 from video tape recording by Serban
    - "Sounding the New Violin" #3 Washington Square Church, NYC`, May 15, 1989; ID: 350.0116; 267298 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0116)
      Side A: 1) "(gamelan) The Gold Stone" Philip Corner 2) "Portrait of Malcolm" Pauline Oliveros Side B: 1) "Koan" James Tenney 2)"Chorals" John Cage 3) "the violin between us..." Bill Hellerman (only beginning)
    - "Soundings", 1996, 2003, 2005; ID: 350.0117; 267366 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0117)
      December 4, 1996: Merkin Hall, NYC (12'02"); November 20, 1996: Ton Art, Bern Kunstmuseum (12'28"); October 12, 2005: International Tagungs fur Improvisation, Lucerne (15'01"); October 12, 2005: International Tagungs fur Improvisation, Lucerne (20'09"); Marche 4, 2003: Western Illinois University New Music Festival (9'04").
    - "Soundings" Brussels, February 6, 1987; ID: 350.0118; 267299 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0118)
      "Soundings for Solo Violin" (with voice) Palais des Beaux Arts Brussels
    - "Soundings" Eighty Layton, March 6, 1982; ID: 350.0119; 267300 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0119)
      "Soundings for Solo Violin" (introductory remarks and set I, II, III)
    - "Soundings" Stockholm, March 26, 1994; ID: 350.0120; 267301 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0120)
    - "Soundings (2)" for solo violin/voice, October 12, 2005; ID: 350.0121; 267367 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0121)
      Recorded at International Tagungs fur Improvisation, Lucerne by Fabian Weibel
    - "Sources of earth and sky" project for CD not realized, 1986, 1988; ID: 350.0122; 267368 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0122)
      1)"Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (13'15"); 2)"Ishi/time changing spaces" (20'07"); 3) "Qerneraq; our breath as bones" (8'28"); 4)"Qerneraq; our breath as bones" (20'24"); 5)"Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (11'28").
    - "Soweto Stomp" Kunstmuseum, Bern, November 20, 1996; ID: 350.0123; 267369 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0123)
      Ton Art concerts, Switzerland. Malcolm Goldstein: violin; Radu Malfatt: trombone; Philippe Micol: bass clarinet; Philippe Racine: flute; Beat Schneider: vocals.
    - "...that hung like fire..." Master; California Institute of the Arts, undated; ID: 350.0124; 267302 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0124)
      Computer tape "I Have a Dream" with Rard Stieger assistance
    - "Theater Piece" John Cage; HR Ensemble for New Music, Frankfurt, November 17, 1995; ID: 350.0125; 267373 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0125)
      1) Violin solo part one; 2) Ensemble complete performance.
    - "Thomas Lehn and Malcolm Goldstein: Recontres de musique spontanees", April 14, 2012; ID: 350.0126; 267380 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0126)
      Live electronics and violin. Rimouski, Quebec.
    - "Three Soundings" live at L'Envers, Montreal, March 12, 2011; ID: 350.0127; 267370 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0127)
      1) 13'45"; 2) 15'35"; 3) 13'35". Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Through deserts of time" String Quartet: Trio Recherche with Malcolm Goldstein, April 23, 1993; ID: 350.0128; 267371 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0128)
      Premier Performance: Wittendays for new music. (26'25") copy from cassette tape.
    - "Tongues of My Mother's Teaching", November 20, 1988; ID: 350.0129; 267303 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0129)
      Montage for "Cycladic Imprints", NYC
    - "Tschaikovsky Decollage" for Barbara Hammann's project, Montreal, September 12, 1996; ID: 350.0130; 267404 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0130)
      Master Tape (33'05")
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind", November, 1994; ID: 350.0131; 267304 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0131)
      Version II with "gentle rain"; WDR Koln, Studio Akustische Kunst
    - "Versuch einer Grundlichen Violin Schule" Master, April 27, 1996; ID: 350.0132; 267305 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0132)
      Studio Akustische Kunst/WDR, Koln
    - "Woodland Patterns" concert, January 23, 1983; ID: 350.0133; 267306 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0133)
      Side One: 1)"Soundings" 2) "The Seasons: Vermont/Winter" Side Two: 1)"Marin's Song, Illuminated" 2)"Soundings"
    - "Yosha's Morning Song" and "Extended", March 4, 1976; ID: 350.0134; 267307 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0134)
      "Yosha's Morning Song" (voice) and "Extended" (instruments) premier: The New Music Ensemble, Dartmouth College
    - "Zwischen (zwei) Raumen", December 12, 1993; ID: 350.0135; 267308 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0135)
      Studio Akustische Kunst: between (two) spaces WDR
  - Subseries B: Interviews, 267145
    Subseries B is comprised of non-commercially released interviews on sound disc and audiocassette. More information about the known contents of each media item is listed below.
    Material is arranged alphabetically by title as found on original media object.
    - Alltagsmusik: Hans Otte, Radio Bremen, April 18, 1996; March 20, 1999; ID: 350.0136; 267395 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0136)
      With excerpts from "my end is my beginning" program with Trio Diritto NachtMusik WDR
    - Ben Young Interview: WKCR, Columbia University Radio NYC (1 of 2), October 3, 2003; ID: 350.0137; 267402 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0137)
      Currently unavailable until duplication.
    - Ben Young Interview: WKCR Columbia University Radio NYC (2 of 2), October 3, 2003; ID: 350.0138; 267403 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0138)
    - Charles Ives: Politics and Aesthetics of a New American Music, Warebrook Festival, July 10, 2004; ID: 350.0139; 267393 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0139)
      (78'28")
    - Karen Frankl presentation, WDR Koln, 1996; ID: 350.0140; 267397 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0140)
      With violin and voice improvisation excerpts and "Vision Tree Soundings" excerpts.
    - Karen Frankl: The Seasons of Malcolm Goldstein, DWR Berlin, 1999; ID: 350.0141; 267396 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0141)
    - Klaus Schoning and Malcolm Goldstein talk: "Ishi/time changing spaces", WDR Koln, undated; ID: 350.0142; 267399 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0142)
      Matera, Italy project. Studio Akustische Kunst.
    - Klaus Schoning and Malcolm Goldstein talk: "Zwischen (zwei) raumen", WDR, Koln, undated; ID: 350.0143; 267398 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0143)
      Studio Akustische Kunst
    - "Le Navire Night": Helene Prevost, Mano Paquet. Societe Radio Canada, Montreal, 1996; ID: 350.0144; 267400 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0144)
      With Swiss Intro: "Le Souffle du Coyote"
    - "The Seasons: Vermont": Frank Hoffman interview, Vermont Public Radio, 1983; ID: 350.0145; 267401 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0145)
- Series VII: Non-commercially Released Video, 267143
  Series VII comprises non-comercially released video VHS and DVD media. More information on the known contents of each individual item is listed below.
  Material is arranged alphabetically by title as designated on the original media item.
  - "All that Rises" film by Daichi Saito, 2007; ID: 350.0146; 267588 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0146)
    Music by Malcolm Goldstein: violin improvisation. Part of the N.Y. Film Festival: Views from the Avant-Garde, Walter Reade Theater, Lincoln Center.
    Original format: DVD
  - "Dacapo Konzart- 200" Goldstein and Kaul, June 12, 1990; ID: 350.0147; 267610 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0147)
    Luneburger Strasse, 2090 Winsen/Luhe
    Original format: VHS
  - Da Capo Performance, Bremen, March 27, 1992; ID: 350.0148; 267582 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0148)
    "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings"; "qerneraq; our breath as bones" With Matthias Kaul. Other performances by Ahmed Essyad, Julio Estrada, Graciela Paraskevaidis, Younghi Pagh-Paan.
  - Dorethea Rust and Malcolm Goldstein: "When your stand still moves" Studio 303, Montreal, February 12, 2011; ID: 350.0149; 267583 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0149)
  - "Espace Ouvert: portraits de Malcolm Goldstein" a film by Thierry Collins, 2007; ID: 350.0150; 267584 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0150)
    Original format: DVD (North American Format)
  - "Field Papers" Dana Reitz at the Brooklyn Academy of Music, February, 1983; ID: 350.0151; 267579 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0151)
    Malcolm Goldstein Solo Violin
    Original format: U-matic
  - "Malcolm on the Roof with a Girl" video by Davidson Gigliotti with Elaine Summers, 1976; ID: 350.0152; 267574 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0152)
  - Merkin Concert Hall: Malcolm Goldstein and Gustavo Matamoros, December 4, 1996; ID: 350.0153; 267573 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0153)
    Music premiers by Malcolm Goldstein: "As it were"; "An enactment of absence"; "Soundings"
  - New Arts Program: Benefit Concert. Kurtztown, PA, April 26, 1990; ID: 350.0154; 267578 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0154)
  - Potluck: Interrelation musical vessels and violin, 1995; ID: 350.0155; 267577 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0155)
  - Real Art Ways: Malcolm Goldstein in Concert, December 5, 1987; ID: 350.0156; 267576 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0156)
    "Soundings" (14"20'); "Out of the Corners" (7'00"); "The Edge of Sound"; "Vision Tree Fragment"
  - "Sounding the New Violin" concert at DCA, NYC, May 5, 1989; ID: 350.0157; 267608 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0157)
    "Eight Whiskus" John Cage; "Crane with 1000 Wings" Louis Vierk; "Trinity" Ornette Coleman; "Sounding the Fragility of Line" Malcolm Goldstein; "Violin and Video" Joseph Celli; "Improvisation" (Encore). Video is copied from original by Serban.
  - "Suspension Reduction" Goldstein, Heward, Wiens, undated; ID: 350.0158; 267609 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0158)
  - "Trees of Syntax, Leaves of Axis" film by Daichi Saito, 2009; ID: 350.0159; 267587 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0159)
    Music by Malcolm Goldstein: "Hues of the Spectrum" violin improvisation.
  - "Uber Land Unter" with Dorethea Rust, Zurich, Switzerland, undated; ID: 350.0160; 267581 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0160)
  - "Z + X Tschaikowsky" Barbara Hammann, 1996; ID: 350.0161; 267575 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0161)
    Munich (complete version)
  - "Zwischen zwei raumen" Westdeutscher Rundfunk Koln, Studio Akustische Kunst, Decampo Film, June 1994; ID: 305.0162; 267580 (Box 42, Media ID: 305.0162)
    "Windowhiskusoundings II"; "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings"; "Gentle rain preceeding mushrooms"
- Series VIII: Data Storage, 267688
  Series VIII comprises data storage on floppy disc and CD-R. More information on known contents of each individual item is listed below.
  Material is listed alphabetically by title as derived from original media item.
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Festival Suoni Per Il Popolo, Montreal, 2008; ID: 350.0164; 267689 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0164)
    Original Format: CD-R with compressed Jpeg and Tiff files
    Currently Unavailable.
  - "Fragments of the Wall" Images by Rehab Nazzal, [undated]; ID: 350.0165; 267690 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0165)
    Original Format: CD-R
  - "Sounding the Full Circle" production, [undated]; ID: 350.0166; 267691 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0166)
    Original Format: 5 1/2" Floppy Disc 3M
- Series IX: Malcolm Goldstein's Notes on the Archive, 267693
  Series IX comprises Malcolm Goldstein's notes describing his collection. In depth lists of music projects, media, and miscellaneous materials were often enclosed with boxes of material upon arrival and reveal more information about how material was originally categorized.
  Materials have been arranged in the order of their corresponding series. For instance, listed information describing Series I: Music Projects was ordered first followed by notes on Series II: Writing. All inventories and lists marked "Miscellaneous" or with multiple entries are at ordered at the end.
  - Music Projects: List of Compositions (1956-2017), 2019, undated; 267694 (Box 43, Folder 1, Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Music Projects: Scores and Performance, 267695 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Music Projects: Other Musicians and Oversize, [undated]; 267696 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Music Projects: Other Musicians and Miscellaneous Tone Roads Materials, October 9, 2012; 267697 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Music Projects: Other Composers and Solo Violin, [undated]; 267698 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Music Projects: Charles Ives Symphony #2 Critical Edition, [undated]; 267699 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Writing: Articles, [undated]; 267700 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Writing: Articles, [undated]; 267701 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Writing: Correspondence, [undated]; 267702 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Writing: Correspondence, [undated]; 267703 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Publicity: Reviews, [undated]; 267704 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Publicity: Concert Programs, [undated]; 267705 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Media: LP Recordings, [undated]; 267737 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Media: Non-Commercial CD Recordings, [undated]; 267738 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Media: Non-Commercial Cassette Recordings Interviews, [undated]; 267739 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Media: Music Compositions on Cassette Tape, [undated]; 267740 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Media: Music Compositions on CD Recordings, [undated]; 267741 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Media: Videos of Performances, [undated]; 267742 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Files: Teaching Positions; Books; Grants, [undated]; 267743 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Files: Resumes; Books; Grants, [undated]; 267744 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Files: Early Concert Programs, [undated]; 267885 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Files: 1952 Image of Goldstein Inspiration, the Juilliard String Quartet, 2019 (Box 53, Folder 9)
- OVERSIZE Series I, 267755
  - Subseries A: Projects A-Z, 267756
    - "Between (two) Spaces" Prix Acustica International Award, September 1993; 1994; 267861 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - "Book of the Dead", 1968; 267817 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" [conductor's score], January 1, 1985; 267818 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" [conductor's score], January 15, 1985; 267819 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - "Cento Anni di Suoni", [undated]; 267878 (Folder 10)
    - "A Convergence of Distances", 1994-1995; 267820 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "Das Erwachen (a cycle of songs)" [1 of 3], 1958-1959; 267757 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "Das Erwachen (a cycle of songs)" corrections [2 of 3], February, 1960; 267758 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Das Erwachen (a cycle of songs)" [3 of 3], 1958-1959; 267759 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Dialogue for Violin and Piano", 1956; 267760 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Dwelling on Dwelling", March 6-April 17, 1994; 267821 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "Emanations" [score], 1962; 267822 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "Episodes for Chamber Orchestra" 1st Movement, October, 1960; 267761 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Episodes for Chamber Orchestra" Movements 1 and 2 [transparencies], October, 1960; 267863 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - "From Wind/ing- Sheet Red Trees Reborn", 1999; 267762 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Improvisation for Piano", December, 1960; 267763 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "In and Out of Silence" with Barbara Hammann and Alison Knowles [inkjet images], September 25-28, 2004; 267823 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - "Karlsplatz Resonanz", 1983; 267879 (Folder 3)